hau.gr 2018-10-13

# Privacy Policy | Hellenic American Union

You are at:  Home / Privacy Policy 

## Hellenic American Union Privacy Policy

Hellenic American Union is committed to protecting your data privacy. 

We invite you to spend some time reading through this Data Privacy Protection Policy (hereafter the “Policy”) and acquaint yourself with the ways in which Hellenic American Union, a non-profit educational and cultural organization in Athens located at Massalias 22, 10680 Athens, tel. 210 36809500, email: [info@hau.gr](mailto:info@hau.gr) (hereafter “HAU”, “we”, “us” or “the HAU”) collects, stores and processes your personal data when you visit or use its website at [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/) and other sites it administers, such as: [http://project.hau.gr](http://project.hau.gr/), [http://digital.hau.gr](http://digital.hau.gr/), [http://designthinking.hau.gr](http://designthinking.hau.gr/) and [http://online.hau.gr](http://online.hau.gr/) (hereafter [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/)), or when you register for a course, examination, service or electronic newsletter. 

Please contact us if you have any questions regarding this policy. 

##### 1\. About the [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/) site 

Our website at [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/) provides you access to a range of services that the HAU offers, such as information on academic programs, educational, social and cultural events, online bookings for events and conferences via [www.eventbrite.com](http://www.eventbrite.com/) and our electronic newsletter.

##### 2\. What are personal data?

The term “personal data” refers to information that can identify an individual who uses the website or one of our services, such as the person’s name, address, email address, and telephone numbers.

##### 3\. What does “processing of personal data” mean?

“Processing” means any operation performed on personal data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, structuring, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure by transmission, dissemination, combination, restriction, erasure or destruction.  

##### 4\. What information is collected via the website?

You can visit our website at [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/) without providing any personal data. In this case, the Internet Service Provider automatically collects a limited number of items of information that are need to operate and assess the site. These items include:

  * the page the user visited
  * the date and time the page was requested
  * the IP address the user’s computer used to receive the information
  * the type and version of the web browser
  * the name and size of the file the user requested

This information is used only for the purpose of helping us evaluate the information services we provide. It is not used to identify our website visitors. None of this information will be disclosed to other organizations or individuals.

The only items of information that can be used to identify individuals are ones that users themselves provide, when sending us a request for information or making a comment or when they apply for admission or register for a course, or when they book a place for an event. This information is used only to respond to the particular request or deliver the requested service. The information is not made public and is provided only to personnel who are authorized to respond to the individual request.

**Information provided on contact forms**

The HAU website provides a contact form where visitors enter their name, email address and their questions or comments. HAU collects and uses this information only to respond to the message. 

**Newsletter Registration**

Visitors to the website have the option to register for the HAU’s electronic newsletter, which provided news of the HAU and information about its academic programs and cultural events, by entering their email address on an online subscription form. Visitors can also register via landing pages that are created as part of a promotional campaign, via an email link to the subscription form or via a printed request form. The subscription form provides information on how the subscriber’s personal information will be used.

HAU collects and processes the information that its visitors provide to communicate with its audience and inform them of educational and cultural programs and services that it develops on its own or in cooperation with other organizations.

Subscribers can unsubscribe from the newsletter at any time, following the unsubscribe link that appears at the bottom of each newsletter. Subscribers can also send an email to [haunewsletter@hau.gr](mailto:haunewsletter@hau.gr) requesting they be deleted from the newsletter subscription list. 

**Course registration**

The HAU website enables visitors to register for training seminars and courses that the HAU offers. We collect and process the information the user provides for the purpose of registering the applicant and communicating with him or her with regard to the seminar and for no other purpose. 

##### 5\. For what purposes does HAU collect personal information?

Visitor information collected automatically by the Internet Service Provider is used strictly for the purposes of operating and assessing the operation of the site. 

The personal information that visitors to the [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/) website enter when completing a contact form, registering for the newsletter, course or book order, or booking the event is used only for the specific purpose for which it is collected, as described above. 

##### 6\. How long do we keep your personal information for?

We do not keep your personal information for longer than is needed the purposes for which we collected it. The table below lists how long we maintain personal data for the main categories of information we collect. The duration may be determined by our contractual, archival and legal obligations to entities such as government authorities and examination boards.

Information you provide when you:

| 

We keep:  
  
---|---  
Register for a language class, professional development seminar |  5 years after the end of the last class or seminar you have taken  
Send your resume or apply a job |  6 months after we receive your application   
Fill out a contact form on one of our websites |  Until we have replied to your request  
Book a place for a cultural event  |  6 months after the event  
Register for a conference |  5 years after the end of the conference  
Sign up for a newsletter |  For as long as you wish to continue receiving the newsletter and have not unsubscribed. If a newsletter is not published for 6 months, we will then delete your personal data.  
Apply to take part in a language certification examination |  60 years after the examination date  
Buy a book from Hellenic American Union publications |  5 years after the purchase  
Sign up for a Facebook competition |  Until the competition has officially ended.  
Take part in a pilot test |  Until you have taken the test and we have issued the results (if this is foreseen).  
Apply to be a proctor or examiner for a certification examination |  10 years after your last exam assignment  
  
##### 7\. What is the legal basis for which HAU processes your personal information?

Personal information provided by the visitor/user of the website [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/) is processed either in the context of fulfilling contractual obligations with the user, as is the case when a user registers to attend a course or a conference, or is based on the user’s own consent, as is the case when a visitor subscribes to receive the HAU’s newsletter or other promotional information. 

Information is processed according to:

  * Your consent to our processing the personal information you provide
  * The terms of our contractual relationship with you
  * Our legal obligations
  * Our legitimate interests

##### 8\. Who do we share your information with?

Depending on your activity on the site, your personal information may be shared with firms we cooperate with when you pay for seminar fees (Viva), book places at events or conferences (EventBrite) or when you take a survey (SurveyMonkey), landing pages created in the context of marketing activities (DirectBookings).

##### 9\. Do we transmit your personal information outside the EU?

We may transmit your data to organizations in the United States if you have registered to take a language competency examination administered by the HAU. These organizations are committed to conforming to the Data Privacy Protection regulations currently in effect in the European Union.

##### 10\. Is your personal information safe?

Protecting your personal information is important to us, and we have taken appropriate organizational, procedural and technical measures for the confidentiality and integrity of your personal data and protection from unauthorized processing. These include physical security measures, strict role-based access to information, network security devices and software. Security safeguards are reviewed periodically and revised when deemed necessary.

Your personal information is processed only by HAU-authorized individuals, staff members, associates and contractual suppliers and only or the purposes described above.

##### 11\. What rights do you have regarding your personal information?

**Right to information**

When we collect your information and at each subsequent stage of processing, you may fully exercise your legal rights, as described below.

When we collect your personal information on the website you have access to this Policy on the home page and every other page of the website [www.hau.gr](http://www.hau.gr/) and its subsites, which provides you:

  * The identity and nature of the communication;
  * The purposes for which the specific information is being collected and the legal basis for doing so;
  * The categories of information collected;
  * The recipients of information;
  * The entities with which information may be shared;
  * Your rights

**Right of access**

You have the right to know if we process your personal information. If we do so, you have the right to ask us what purposes we are processing the information for, what kind of information we keep, who we share it with, how long we keep it for, whether we use it to automate decision-making and what your other rights are, such as the rights of rectification, erasure, and restriction of processing, as well as the submission of complaint to the Data Privacy Protection Authority.

You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.

**Right to rectification**

You have the right to ask us to correct any incomplete or inaccurate information we hold about you.

**Right to erasure**

You may ask us to delete or remove personal information where there is no longer a good reason for us to continue to process it. You also have the right to withdraw your consent when this constitutes the sole legal basis for processing your information.

**Right of portability**

You may ask to provide you with a copy of your personal information in a commonly used, machine-readable form or to transfer your information to another data processor. 

**Right to request restriction of processing**

You may ask us to suspend the processing of personal information about you, for example, if you want us to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it.

**Right to object and withdrawal of consent for processing your information**

You may object to us processing your information and we cease during so if there are no urgent and legal reasons that supersede this right. In circumstances where you may have provided your consent to the collection, processing and transfer of your personal information for a specific purpose, you have the right to withdraw your consent for that specific processing at any time.

##### 12\. How can you exercise your rights?

To exercise your data privacy rights, you may contact us at 210 3680056 or via email at [privacy@hau.gr](mailto:privacy@hau.gr). To expedite your request, we suggest you use one of the following procedures to submit your data privacy request:

  * send an email to [privacy@hau.gr](mailto:privacy@hau.gr) include a scanned copy of a signed request (with attestation of the authenticity of the signature) or attach a certified digital signature. We will respond to the email you have indicated unless you request that it be sent in another way.
  * fill out the request, have your signature authenticated at a Citizens' Service Center (KEP) or police station and mail it to us at Hellenic American Union, Massalias 22, 10680 Athens.
  * present your request in person at the HAU at (Massalias 22, 10680, Athens. If you submit your request in person, you do not need to verify the authenticity of your signature, but we will ask for identification, such as your identity card or other official document; in all other cases, special authorization detailing your request is required.

##### 13\. When will we respond to your request?

We will promptly respond to your request without charge and within one (1) month of receiving it. However, if your request is complex or contains a large number of items, we may need an extension of two additional months in order to respond.

If you request is manifestly unfounded or repetitive, HAU may make a reasonable charge for responding to your request in light of the administrative costs for providing the information or implemented the requesting action, or it may refuse to pursue your request.

##### 14\. Who do you contact to find out about the status of your request?

Contact us at 210 3680056.

##### 15\. Do we use automated individual decision-making, including profiling, in processing your information?

We do not make decisions or construct profiles on the basis of information processed automatically. We use cookies on our website and provide you with information on how they are used and how you may disable their use.

##### 16\. What is the legal framework for processing your personal information?

We process your data in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) 2016/679 of the European Union, and in general the existing national and European legislative and regulatory framework for data privacy. The competent court for any dispute arising from issues relating to your personal information is the Court of Athens.

##### 17\. Where can you file a complaint about us if you believe we have breached your data privacy

You have the right to file a complaint with the Data Privacy Protection Authority (www.dpa.gr) if you believe that we have breached the law governing data privacy in processing your personal information. 

##### 18\. How can I be informed of changes in this Policy?

We will update this Policy as required. If there are important changes to the Policy or in the way we use your personal information, we will inform you before implementing these changes by publishing a prominently placed announcement or with other appropriate means. We encourage you to periodically consult this Policy to keep informed of your personal information is protected.

##### 19\. Cookies Policy

You can find information about Hellenic American Union’s Cookies Policy here.

* * *

For additional information regarding this Policy, and for any other matter concerning how we process your personal information and how you can exercise your data privacy rights, contact us  at +210 3680056, at Massalias 22, 10680 Athens or via email at [privacy@hau.gr](mailto:privacy@hau.gr).

**Last Update At:** 2018/07/04 - 15:17:03
